Daniel Cárdenas

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

Monterrev. NL. México

□ (+52) 8114140740 | 🗷 danielcardeenas@gmail.com | 🏕 danielcardeenas.github.io | 🖸 danielcardeenas | 🖹 danielcardeenas

"Create."

Summary.

I am a passionate software engineer and work addict. 7+ Experience creating systems from scratch involving all layers of the software development process. Love creating great things with better quality and focus on it's scalability that will impact the world.

Work Experience

Cemex (Neoris).

Prague, CZ | Remote | Monterrey, MX

LEAD SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

Dec. 2016 - PRESENT

- Made architecture of web application, code reviews and coaching to my teammates to ensure the code quality and maintainability and, most
 important, scalability. Planned every requirement and new features from project managers to developers. From CI, branching, feature releasing, testing to code logic itself. Application is deployed in 25+ countries and is suited to support more in almost no-time. DevOps side is mainly
 deployed with Jenkins inside Azure slots.
- (Track & Trace) Software engineer in application for Cemex clients.

Mi Chance (Manufacture).

Remote | Mérida, MX | Monterrey, MX

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

Sep. 2018 - PRESENT

• Define requirements with product owners. Develop every layer of the system which is based on Google cloud platform. Cost effectiveness and performance are key in this project due to the budget of the investors. So the stack of the application uses Google cloud compute engines (separated api, and frontend) which both are auto scalable due to the user traffic. Uses Datastore as main database source (NoSQL) which is built on top of colossus and Megastore for extra good performance. Averything is versioned and built automatically with CircleCI + Gitlab into their corresponding environments. Front end applications are developed in Kotlin and Angular

Oxxo Monterrey, MX

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT & (LEAD DEVELOPER)

Nov. 2015 - Dec. 2016

• Designed and implemented of a kiosk system for selected Oxxos stores. Kiosks are connected to their respective POS system and are optimized to work 24/7. The application patches and updates itself remotely.

Buro Creativo. Remote | Monterrey

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

Jun. 2016 - Oct. 2016

Created of custom CRM system that was later sold to this company so their developers can maintain it and develop above it. The stack used
 x for this application is mainly .NET Core and it's deployed into Azure

ION Water Distributor Remote

SOLUTION ARCHITECT (FULLSTACK DEVELOPER)

Jul. 2014 - Ene. 2016

• Developed a whole custom ERP system from scratch. Architecture of the application is based on modules which are easily added to the system as the client needs. This system is deployed into the client servers which used IIS. and still running. The stack used here is T-SQL, .NET MVC

Freelancing & Own Projects

PROJECTS

2016 C++ api library for Quandl, Best Quandl library out there. Built in C++.

2017 • Whatsapp framework, Python framework for whatsapp bots creation. Built in Python. Home

2014 • Audio Stego, Stenography tool. Built in C++.

Home

CANSLIM strategy implementation, Scraps data from Quandl, Yahoo finance, etc... To do the

fundamental analysis explained in the William O'Neil book. Drops similar results to the IDB Leaderboard.

Home
Built in C++.

FREELANCER

2016 Quandl retriver (tecenergy.ca), Quandl big data retriever for data science firm active in financial electricity markets. Built in C# and PostgreSQL.

Montreal, CA

,

January 22, 2019 Daniel Cardenas · Résumé

Coures_

Acceleration program

California, US

PLug & PLay Sep. 2015 - Nov. 2015

· Daily workshops focused on how produce a fast app launching for startups, marketing, innovation, etc...

Machine Learning A-Z™: Hands-On Python & R In Data Science

Remote

Nov. 2018 - Present

• Machine learning course

Education

UDEMY

UANL - FIME(Universidad Autonoma de Nuevo León)

Monterrey, MX

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug. 2011 - Exp. Nov. 2015

• Paused at my last semester to focus on my work.

Curses provided

UANL (FACPYA)

Monterrey, MX

OOP with C# Feb. 2016 - PRESENT

• Taught OOP with C to the students of my own university from another career. How to use Interop libraries, to automatize tasks from Excel data using LINQ.

Languages I speak

Spanish Fluent,

English Fluent,

Italian Advanced,

Japanese Basic,